<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>excel on Stupid Spreadsheets</title>
    <link>https://rosespreadsheet.com/tags/excel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in excel on Stupid Spreadsheets</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rosespreadsheet.com/tags/excel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Forget VLookup if You&#39;re Using Office 365</title>
      <link>https://rosespreadsheet.com/post/xlookup-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosespreadsheet.com/post/xlookup-function/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;re currently using Office 365, then relying on VLookup is a waste of time :D
Because XLookup will become your best friend forever. Here&amp;rsquo;s how it works:
```=XLOOKUP(lookup_value, lookup_array, return_array, [if_not_found], [match_mode], [search_mode])```  Note that the arguments in square brackets are optional
As you may know, VLookup can only look for the data from left to right, not the oposite. With XLookup, you can do both ways. Let&amp;rsquo;s go straight to an example:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip #2 - Copy Formula Down or to The Right</title>
      <link>https://rosespreadsheet.com/post/tip-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosespreadsheet.com/post/tip-2/</guid>
      <description>Another interesting tip I want to share is to copy formula down or to the right by using your keyboard.
Suppose you have a formula in Cell A1 and want to drag the formula down to A10. Instead of using your mouse to do it, alternatively, you can also do the following:
Select A1 -&amp;gt; Ctrl + Shift + Down Arrow until you reach A10, or you can just simply select range A1:A10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tip #1 - How to Remove or Automatically Update Links in a Speadsheet</title>
      <link>https://rosespreadsheet.com/post/tip-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosespreadsheet.com/post/tip-1/</guid>
      <description>My colleagues often wonder how I could solve excel problems in seconds and everything about excel seems so easy for me. The answer is I know some interesting tips that can help me find the problem quickly. Here is one of them.
Suppose you open an excel speadsheet and this message pops up: &amp;ldquo;This workbook contains links to one or more external sources that could be unsafe.&amp;rdquo;
1. Find The Links and Remove Them You find this message annoying and want to remove all the links in the workbook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Lookup Functions for Excel and Google Sheets</title>
      <link>https://rosespreadsheet.com/post/lookup-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rosespreadsheet.com/post/lookup-functions/</guid>
      <description>Scenario: You are assigned to manage 5 items from the purchasing manager. In the systems the company is using, you exported a list of all products they have as well as the data of the stock on hand (SOH), you would like to look for the product names and the stock on hand from the codes given.
First, download your practice sheet here: https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1G5aJb4IUIJfac0PBnGZ9gDHB4ku3RT2R?usp=sharing
Here are what you can do on your spreadsheet to look for the information more quickly and effectively:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
